# **Gabriel Pettus**

Denver, CO 80205 Phone: 303-243-2460 | Email: gabe.pettus@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/gabepettus

I am an experienced system engineer with a bachelor's degree in physics and mathematics and have completed a full stack development bootcamp at the University of Denver. I want to shift my career focus to crafting software as a junior-level developer.

## Skills and Technical Experience

### **Development Tools**

Some of tools with which I am familiar:

HTML; CSS; PHP; React; Bootstrap; AJAX; Materialize; Node.js; Express;
Mongo/Mongoose; Oracle; MySQL; Sequelize; SQL; Rest APIs; JSON; Git; bash; Perl;
regex; Agile; Jira; Confluence

### **Working with Users**

I have worked with users in many ways, including:

- Translating user operational needs to software requirements
- Sitting with operators in their daily work environment to provide ongoing training and troubleshooting
- Creating and maintaining tools to automate and augment routine operator and system tasks
- Providing software demos to users, customers, and management
- Providing software training in lecture and on-the-job format
- Providing 24 hour on-call support for high availability, critical systems

#### Communication

My jobs have always included continual communication with stakeholders. Examples include:

- Repeated recognition for my ability to communicate and work directly with customers and operators, bridge strong personalities, and build stakeholder consensus (or at least reluctant agreement)
- Organizing and facilitating technical exchange meetings between (sometime hostile) venders, customer, and / or users
- Presenting technical designs and concept of operations changes to users and customers in presentations, interactive discussion, and hands-on demos throughout the maturation of the software
- Creating and maintaining software documentation, including interface control documents; APIs; test/training plan and materials; evidence of security compliance; and requirements
- Developing and presenting training course material

### **Testing**

My experience includes:

- Creating and executing internal and formal requirement, functional, interface, performance, and regression test procedures
- Utilization of jest on some school projects

## **Professional Experience**

Senior Systems Engineer, Feb. 2019 - present ICR Inc, Aurora, CO

I provide demos to and facilitate written and oral communication with both working-level and senior-level customers. I work with the software team to ensure software and schedule goals are met and to ensure a customer-focused product. I assist the business development teams with white papers and proposals.

Senior Systems Engineer, Nov. 2013 - Feb. 2019 CACI/BITSystems, Aurora, CO

As both a team member and baseline lead through several software development cycles, I was responsible for and executed tasks at each stage of the software development process including: initial design and proposal/negotiation; requirement development; ensuring requirements are satisfied; schedule and team planning; performed scrum product owner and master functions; integration coordination; witness testing; execution of training; delivery and integration support. I frequently made formal and informal presentations to customers and users. I also created documentation including interface control documents (APIs); test/training plan and materials; evidence of security compliance; and requirements.

Senior Systems Engineer 2 with Honors (last position), May 2001 - Nov. 2013 Raytheon Company, Aurora, CO

I provided embedded 24/7 support to operations. I worked closely with operators, customer representatives, and our software team at the factory to troubleshoot and document problems. Additionally, I developed and maintained a script (CSS, HTML, PERL, SQL, JavaScript, csh, bash) baseline to supplement operational needs which were not met by our software. I finished my career at Raytheon working on test and integration teams.

## **Education & Certifications**

- Certificate: Full Stack Web Development from University of Denver
- Certificate: CompTIA Security+
- Bachelor of Science: Metropolitan State Collection of Denver (now Metropolitan University of Denver), Mathematics and Physics Double Major